<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Elizabeth Luh</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Elizabeth Luh</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2030 13:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Recent &amp; Upcoming Talks</title>
      <link>/talk/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2030 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses</title>
      <link>/courses/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/courses/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Posts</title>
      <link>/post/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slides</title>
      <link>/slides/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/slides/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>/project/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research</title>
      <link>/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/research/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;working-papers&#34;&gt;Working Papers&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;not-so-black-and-white-uncovering-racial-bias-from-systematically-misreported-trooper-reports&#34;&gt;Not so Black and White: Uncovering Racial Bias from Systematically Misreported Trooper Reports&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Highway police officers, or troopers, may misreport the race of people that they engage with in order to evade detection of racial bias. I propose a new test of racial bias in the presence of misreporting that is well-suited to explore the rich heterogeneity in bias behavior. Using a unique event in Texas where troopers were caught deliberately misreporting minority motorists as white, I find bias against all minority motorists, but especially against Hispanic motorists. I estimate bias for each trooper and find that over 30% of troopers were engaging in this behavior. Using my trooper level measure of bias, I identify causal relationships between bias and labor outcomes using a panel data set of trooper employment outcomes. I show misreporting was used effectively to evade detection of bias, with bias having no effect on labor market outcomes when the misreporting was possible. I find that after a rule change to trooper stop recording policy in response to the misreporting led to negative labor outcomes for biased troopers, specifically, lower rates of promotion and had lower salary growth. I further test how individual trooper bias changes in response to changes in peer, demographic compositions. In particular, black or Hispanic troopers are sensitive to changes in peer composition, while white troopers are unaffected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Job Market Paper (most recent draft here)&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;works-in-progress&#34;&gt;Works in Progress&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;disparate-fine-collection-evidence-using-chicago-parking-tickets&#34;&gt;Disparate Fine Collection: Evidence using Chicago Parking Tickets&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using a plausibly exogenous increase in the fine for failing to purchase annual vehicle registration in 2012, colloquially known as the sticker tax, I test if Chicago police disparately enforced parking compliance across black and non-black neighborhoods from 2007 to 2017. I find that police behavior is responsive to the penalty structure of the fine and are 20 to 50 percent more likely to apply the sticker fine to black neighborhoods after the increase. This disparate enforcement is robust to employment controls and is not driven by changing compliance rates across neighborhoods. In contrast, I find that parking enforcement agents do not disparately enforce the tickets across black and non-black neighborhoods. I attribute this difference in behavior between parking enforcement agents and police officers to the lack of work evaluations based on ticketing productivity for police officers. Since police officers are not evaluated by their parking citation productivity, they do not behave as revenue-maximizing agents in the context of parking enforcement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;effects-of-incarceration-on-childrens-schooling-outcomes&#34;&gt;Effects of Incarceration on Children&amp;rsquo;s Schooling Outcomes&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Roughly over 2 million people are incarcerated in the United States annually. While incarceration is necessary to maintain the safety and peace of innocent citizens, anecdotal research has found harmful effects on children in neighborhoods with high incarceration. Using administrative panel data for over 70,000 public school students in Houston, Texas and using inmate addresses to construct the incarceration rate by school zone, I evaluate the effect of a drop in incarceration rates at the school zone level for drug crimes on children&amp;rsquo;s educational outcomes. Since high incarceration rates and negative schooling outcomes for children are correlated to poor neighborhood quality, I use the downgrading in the punishment of being caught with a trace amount of drugs from a felony to a misdemeanor as an exogenous shock to the incarceration rate. I find limited overall effects on children&amp;rsquo;s test scores, but find behavioral improvements in children&amp;rsquo;s schooling outcomes. (*Note: This paper is embargoed per data use agreement. Please reach out by email for a copy of this paper.)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
