<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Elizabeth Luh</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Elizabeth Luh</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses</title>
      <link>/courses/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/courses/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Posts</title>
      <link>/post/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slides</title>
      <link>/slides/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/slides/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>/project/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CV</title>
      <link>/cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cv/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Download my CV &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/elizluh/papers/raw/master/CV.pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;here&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research</title>
      <link>/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/research/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;working-papers&#34;&gt;Working Papers&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;the-impact-of-financial-sanctions-in-the-us-justice-system-regression-discontinuity-evidence-from-michigans-driver-responsibility-program&#34;&gt;The Impact of Financial Sanctions in the U.S. Justice System: Regression Discontinuity Evidence from Michigan&amp;rsquo;s Driver Responsibility Program&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&#34;joint-with-keith-finlay-matthew-gross-and-michael-mueller-smith&#34;&gt;(joint with Keith Finlay, Matthew Gross, and Michael Mueller-Smith)&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We estimate the causal impact of financial sanctions in the U.S. criminal justice system. We utilize a regression discontinuity design and exploit two distinct natural experiments: the abrupt introduction of driver responsibility fees (DRF) in Michigan and Texas. These discontinuously imposed additional surcharges ($300–$6,000) for criminal traffic offenses. Although the policies generated almost $3 billion of debt, we find consistent evidence that the DRFs had no impact on recidivism, earnings, or romantic partners’ outcomes over the next decade. Without evidence of a general or specific deterrence effect and modest success with debt collection, we find little justification for these policies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Download most recent version &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/elizluh/papers/raw/master/finsanc.pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;here&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;not-so-black-and-white-uncovering-racial-bias-from-systematically-misreported-trooper-reports&#34;&gt;Not so Black and White: Uncovering Racial Bias from Systematically Misreported Trooper Reports&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Biased highway troopers may intentionally misreport the race of the stopped motorists in order to evade detection. I develop a new model of traffic stops that highlights the incentive for biased troopers to misreport their failed minority searches as White. Applying my model to the universe of highway searches in Texas from 2010&amp;ndash;2015, I find evidence of widespread bias that varies substantially across troopers. When misreporting became more difficult due to public scrutiny, biased troopers faced worse labor outcomes. This suggest an important role for increased accountability in data collection by law enforcement agents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Download most recent version &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/elizluh/papers/blob/master/notsoblackandwhite.pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;here&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;works-in-progress&#34;&gt;Works in Progress&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;disparate-fine-collection-evidence-using-chicago-parking-tickets&#34;&gt;Disparate Fine Collection: Evidence using Chicago Parking Tickets&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using a plausibly exogenous increase in the fine for failing to purchase annual vehicle registration in 2012, colloquially known as the sticker tax, I test if Chicago police disparately enforced parking compliance across black and non-black neighborhoods from 2007 to 2017. I find that police behavior is responsive to the penalty structure of the fine and are 20 to 50 percent more likely to apply the sticker fine to black neighborhoods after the increase. This disparate enforcement is robust to employment controls and is not driven by changing compliance rates across neighborhoods. In contrast, I find that parking enforcement agents do not disparately enforce the tickets across black and non-black neighborhoods. I attribute this difference in behavior between parking enforcement agents and police officers to the lack of work evaluations based on ticketing productivity for police officers. Since police officers are not evaluated by their parking citation productivity, they do not behave as revenue-maximizing agents in the context of parking enforcement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Download most recent version &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/elizluh/papers/raw/master/parking%20bias2.pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;here&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
