<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Elizabeth Luh</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Elizabeth Luh</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2030 13:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Recent &amp; Upcoming Talks</title>
      <link>/talk/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2030 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Posts</title>
      <link>/post/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slides</title>
      <link>/slides/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/slides/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>/project/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link></link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid></guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses</title>
      <link>/courses/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/courses/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research</title>
      <link>/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/research/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;working-papers&#34;&gt;Working Papers&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;not-so-black-and-white-uncovering-racial-bias-from-systematically-misreported-trooper-reports&#34;&gt;Not so Black and White: Uncovering Racial Bias from Systematically Misreported Trooper Reports&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Highway police officers, or troopers, may misreport the race of people that they engage with in order to evade detection of racial bias. I propose a new test of racial bias in the presence of misreporting that is well-suited to explore the rich heterogeneity in bias behavior. Using a unique event in Texas where troopers were caught deliberately misreporting minority motorists as white, I find bias against all minority motorists, but especially against Hispanic motorists. I estimate bias for each trooper and find that nearly 60% of troopers were engaging in this behavior. Using my trooper level measure of bias, I identify causal relationships between bias and labor outcomes using a panel data set of trooper employment outcomes. I show misreporting was used effectively to evade detection of bias, with bias having no effect on labor market outcomes when the misreporting was possible. I find that after a rule change to trooper stop recording policy in response to the misreporting led to negative labor outcomes for biased troopers, specifically, lower rates of promotion and had lower salary growth. I further test how individual trooper bias changes in response to changes in peer, demographic compositions. In particular, black or Hispanic troopers are sensitive to changes in peer composition, while white troopers are unaffected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;/files/highwaybias.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Job Market Paper (most recent draft here)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;works-in-progress&#34;&gt;Works in Progress&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;long-term-effects-of-racial-bias-evidence-using-chicago-parking-tickets&#34;&gt;Long term effects of racial bias: evidence using Chicago parking tickets&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Biased application of parking laws may have greater detrimental effects on neighborhoods than previously estimated. Using an exogeneous increase in the fine for vehicle registration in Chicago enacted in 2017, I am able to test and measure racial bias in parking enforcement. I find that the increase in fines in black neighborhoods led to a 5% increase in driver&amp;rsquo;s license suspension, a 1% increase in bankruptcy declarations, and 10% increase in policing compared to white neighborhoods before and after the fine increase.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;effects-of-incarceration-on-children-s-schooling-outcomes&#34;&gt;Effects of Incarceration on Children&amp;rsquo;s Schooling Outcomes&lt;/h4&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
